<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Subham Kailthya on Subham Kailthya</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Subham Kailthya on Subham Kailthya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Subham Kailthya</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerability of Households to Weather Shocks and the Mitigating Role of Workfare Programs</title>
      <link>/publication/weather-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/weather-stress/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to Productivity: The Effect of Roads on Manufacturing TFP in India</title>
      <link>/publication/roads-asi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/roads-asi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing India&#39;s slums: Informality and exceptionalism vs. formality and rules in public service provision</title>
      <link>/publication/pol-slums/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pol-slums/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The heterogeneous effect of political competition on government responsiveness in India</title>
      <link>/publication/pol-health-qr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pol-health-qr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Competition and Government Responsiveness: Evidence from Rural India</title>
      <link>/publication/pol-health-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pol-health-iv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>/project/climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/climate-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerability of households to weather shocks and the mitigating role of workfare programs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing variability in the weather poses major economic and non-economic challenges especially for rural areas of developing countries. While some socioeconomic factors mitigate weather-induced burden, others work to intensify impact. I examine how these factors intersect to affect weather-induced burden at the household-level. I focus on establishing the causal effects of weather shocks on household living standards, and evaluate the impact of public policies, such as workfare programs, in mitigating weather-induced impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings from this project are extremely relevant for policy makers in understanding the heterogeneous impact of climate change. It also evaluates the role of public safety nets in building climate resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firms</title>
      <link>/project/firms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/firms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Drives Manufacturing Productivity? What Are The Productivity Gains From Lower Transport Costs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role of manufacturing in economic growth cannot be overemphasized. For manufacturing to reach its full potential however, requires closely concerted investments in infrastructure, training, research, etc. that enable firms to fully utilise the pool of human and physical resources at its disposal. Understanding what boosts manufacturing is important not only because of its high contribution to overall GDP, but also because it creates many new jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with my co-author, I aim to understand the macroeconomic conditions that influence the efficiency of manufacturing. We then take a closer look at the impact of lower transportation costs on manufacturing productivity in India using establishment-level panel data during 1998-2012.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Economics</title>
      <link>/project/political-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/political-economics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do political-economic factors affect governemnt responsiveness? What explains the heterogeneity in the provision of public goods?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments play an important welfare-enhancing role. In developing countries, public services are often deficient and of poor quality. Why does democracy struggle to ensure the provision of public services in developing countries? To understand this, I examine the relationship between different political-economic factors and government responsiveness at the sub-national level in India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructural Development and Firm Efficiency in India (1999-2007)</title>
      <link>/publication/infrastructure-tfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/infrastructure-tfp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
